Guide to the Barclay Jones papers, 1954-1988
Jones, Barclay papers, 1954-1988
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Barclay Jones papers, 1954-1988
15-2-2552
Barclay G. Jones
42.4 cubic ft.
Vitae, bibliography, reprints, books, and correspondence
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Vitae, bibliography, reprints, and books. Also, correspondence, project files, subject files relating to the University and the Department of City and Regional planning, and other papers.
SUBJECTS
Titles:
Regional Science Newsletter.
Subjects:
Cornell University. College of Architecture, Art, and Planning.; City planning--Study and teaching.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
RELATED MATERIALS
Collecting program: Lambda Alpha Literary Archives.
Collecting program: Regional Science Archives.
COLLECTION ARRANGEMENT
Arranged by subject.
CONTAINER LIST
- Autobiographical material, personal, vitae (Box 1)
- Correspondence: A-K, 1952-1969 (Box 1)
- Correspondence: L-W, 1943-1969 (Box 2)
- Correspondence: A-B, 1970-1983 (Box 2)
- Correspondence: Ba-Finch, C., 1970-1983 (Box 3)
- Correspondence: Finch, G.-Ki, 1970-1984 (Box 4)
- Correspondence: Kn-Parker, 1961-1984 (Box 5)
- Correspondence: Parsons-Theil, 1970-1984 (Box 6)
- Correspondence: Thorbeck-U, 1960-1984 (Box 7)
- Correspondence: V-Z, 1965-1986 (Box 8)
- Cornell materials: faculty meetings, correspondence, 1966-1977 (Box 8)
- Course materials, 1959-1975 (Box 9)
  AAP 845, APP 917, CP 100, CP 121
- Course materials, 1957-1987 (Box 10)
  CP 121, CPG 1, CPG 6, CPG 12, CPG 299, CRP 400
- Course materials, 1969-1996 (Box 11)
  CRP 400, CRP 401, CRP 402, CRP 433/733, CRP 440/540, Planning 531, Planning 533, CRP 570, CRP 585, CRP620
- Course materials, 1968-1994 (Box 12)
  CRP 620, PPRA 644, PPRA 645, CRP 664
- Course materials, 1961-1995 (Box 13)
  CRP 664, Planning 701, Planning 410/710, Planning 711, Planning 712/CP 100, Planning 714, Planning 715, Planning 716, Planning 717, Planning 719, Planning 720, Planning 722, Planning 730
- Course materials, 1961-1977 (Box 14)
  CRP 730, CRP 731, CRP 732, CRP 433/733, CRP 440/740, CRP 749, CRP 737, CRP 739, CRP 740, CRP 747
- Course materials, 1967-1996 (Box 15)
  Planning 770, CRP 789, CRP 800, CRP 801
- Course materials, 1954-1996 (Box 16)
  CRP 810, CRP/PPRA 844, PPRA 877, PPRA 916, CRP 917, CRP 920, Misc. Courses Fall 1978, M. E. 3240, Summer Institute, Traffic Seminar; BGJ student work
- BGJ student work; Agnes files; AIP files; Bucks County, Pennsylvania project, 1959-1989 (Box 17)
- Bucks County, Pennsylvania project; Center for Urban Development Research, 1969-1979 (Box 18)
- Charleston, South Carolina; China, Consulting: SWCF, Urban Configuration proposal, 1962-1995 (Box 19)
- Consulting, 1964-1974 (Box 20)
  Cape May County, Wayne County, Wilkes-Barre, Penna., Wyoming Valley, Chenango County; Disaster Prevention seminar; Earthquakes: 1972 Yugoslavia (NSF project)
- Earthquakes, 1972-1985 (Box 21)
  Yugoslavia (NSF project), Italy (1981), Third International Conference
- Earthquakes, 1984-1985 (Box 22)
  Yugoslavia, Third International Conference
- Earthquakes, 1985 (Box 23)
  Third International Conference
- Earthquakes, 1985 (Box 24)
- Earthquakes, 1985-1993 (Box 25)
  Third International Conference, NCEER
- Earthquakes, 1990-1995 (Box 26)
  NCEER
- Earthquakes, 1964-1991 (Box 27)
  Kunming Symposium, publications; other conferences: International Seminar on Regional Development Planning for Disaster Prevention
- Other conferences, 1982, 1986 (Box 28)
  Museum Conference (1982, 1986), Soviet Seminar (1982)
- Other conferences, 1966- 1986 (Box 29)
  Soviet Seminar (1982); Wingspread Conference; Preservation Planning
- Projects, 1964-1995 (Box 30)
  Agnes, Barranquitas, P.R., Iran, Lehigh-Northampton Counties, Memphis, OWRR, Onondaga County, Syracuse Five County Study Area, Tompkins County: Clinton House, Taggin Wagon, Baldwin residence, Randall-Dana shopping center, Franzen; Proposals: Amman
- Proposals, 1963-1980 (Box 31)
  Atlanta, C. U. Housing and Environmental Studies, C. U. Planning - 50 years, indoor air pollution, Malaysian project, museum and earthquake seminar proposal, NDEA fellowships, NSF, Tanzania; PPRA
- PPRA, 1969-1976 (Box 32)
- PPRA, PURS, 1972-1985 (Box 33)
- PURS; Arthur Reed project files: Cortlandville, Lysander, Ticonderoga, Syracuse, Onondaga County, 1961-1979 (Box 34)
- Arthur Reed project files, 1957-1969 (Box 35)
  Baldwinsville, Lysander, Elbridge, Jordan, Jefferson County, Webster, Cortlandville, McGraw, Cortland County, Wilna Champion
- Arthur Reed project files, 1964-1979 (Box 36)
  Wilna Champion; Wayne County; Ontario; Warren, Pa.; Canastota, N.Y.; BGJ consulting: Tourism Development in Korea; Central New York State; Delhi, Ithaca; Project: Schoharie; Urban Affairs/Urban Studies
- Urban Affairs/Urban Studies; BGJ miscellany; Articles, Talks, Publications: Architecture, Building Economics, City Planning [see also Urban Studies], Civil Engineering, Cost Estimation, Demographics, Design [see also Architecture], Development, Economic, 1951-1986 (Box 37)
- Articles, Talks, Publications, 1955-1993 (Box 38)
  Development, Economic; Disasters
- Articles, Talks, Publications, 1955-1984 (Box 39)
  Disasters; Economics; Funding; Information Systems; Land Use [see also planning]; Landscape Architecture; Models
- Articles, Talks, Publications, 1954-1987 (Box 40)
  Planning, Education; Planning, Health; Planning, Organizations; Planning Studies; Population Studies; Preservation; Preservation, Historic Towns; Regional Development
- Articles, Talks, Publications, 1954-1992 (Box 41)
  Regional Development; Regional Plans by location
- Articles, Talks, Publications, 1959-1983 (Box 42)
  Regional Plans by location; Regional Science; Research, Administration; Social Sciences; Urban Studies, Urban Studies, Methods; illustrations for book
- Illustrations for book, miscellaneous prints, negatives and one film, n.d. (Box 43)